
<web title='Download'>

<line title='Source'>

A web view of the source is available <link src='source'>here</link>
(~0.5Mb). And there is a JAR that contains it all available
<a href='/src.zip'>here</a>.
You will also need a lib directory which unzipped from
<a href='http://www.eireneh.demon.co.uk/projectb/lib.zip'>here</a>
(~2.5Mb) and placed like this
<pre>
jsword
 |--classes                 Compiled Java files
 |   `--com
 |       `--eireneh ...
 |--lib                     Other files
 |   |--config              properties files
 |   |--cookies             servlet cookie data
 |   |--jars                libraries
 |   |--logs                error/event logs
 |   |--styles              XSL transform files
 |   |   |--page            Bible data -> Page data
 |   |   |--swing           Bible data -> HTMLEditorKit data
 |   |   |--test            XSL testing
 |   |   `--web             Page data -> HTML
 |   |--versions            Bible data
 |   |   |--jdbc            Access database pointers
 |   |   |--raw             Raw format data
 |   |   `--ser             Ser format data
 |   `--web                 XML files for the web
 `--src                     Java source files
     `--com
         `--eireneh ...
</pre>
However if you actually want to develop with any of this stuff, then
please <link src='contact'>tell me</link>. The source you can see is
almost certainly out of date, and it would make sense to share more
current code.

</line>
<line title='Libraries'>

You will need a few extra libraries to compile all this lot. If you must
compile absolutely everything for JDK v1.1 then you will all of these. If
you want everything for JDK v1.2 then exclude Swing and Collections. You
can also exclude Swing support by excluding packages that contain the
word swing, Servlet and Mail support can also be excluded in a similar
way. Clearly if you don't compile with servlet support, then you can't
use servlets, and so on. This is not a 100% rule, but it is an aim.

<ul>

<li><b>XML4J:</b> from <a href='http://www.alphaworks.ibm.com'>IBM alphaWorks</a>
    This turns XML strings into an in memory DOM model. You can get it
    from <a href='http://www.alphaworks.ibm.com/tech/xml4j'>here</a></li>

<li><b>LotusXSL:</b> also from <a href='http://www.alphaworks.ibm.com'>alphaWorks</a>
    Takes the XML generated by the Bible sources and formats it for
    the current display. You can download it from
    <a href='http://www.alphaworks.ibm.com/tech/lotusxsl'>here</a></li>

<li><b>Swing:</b> You only need this if you are not using JDK 1.2. You can download it
    <a href='http://java.sun.com/products/jfc/index.html#download-swing'>here</a>
    You can use Swing v1.1, but I strongly recommend v.1.1.1</li>

<li><b><a href='http://www.javasoft.com/products/jdk/1.2/docs/guide/collections/'>Collections:</a></b>
    Also not needed if you are on 1.2 or later. The collections for
    JDK 1.1 link seems to have disappeared from Sun's site, I guess they
    want to encourage people to use 1.2. However for quite a few people
    Psion users and Linux users for example, JDK 1.2 is not an easy
    option, so the other solution is to use JGL instead. I'd rather save
    people the extra download for 1.2 though. Anyhow you can get
    Collections for 1.1 <a href='/download/collections.jar'>here</a>. Or
    cheat and use the InfoBus v1.2 download area which is linked
    <a href='http://java.sun.com/beans/infobus/index.html#DOWNLOAD_COLLECTIONS'>
    here</a>.</li>

<li><b>Servlet Support:</b> can be downloaded from JavaSoft
    <a href='http://www.javasoft.com/products/servlet/'>here</a> try
    JSWDK v1.0. However if you are doing Servlets then you probably have a
    Servlet Server, which should have this.</li>

<li><b>Javax Mail and JAF:</b> also from JavaSoft can be downloaded from
    <a href='http://www.javasoft.com/products/javamail/'>here</a></li>

</ul>

All this stuff will all work with JDK 1.1 and up, you just have a longer
download if you're not at 1.2.

</line>

</web>
